

Full Stack Developer jmpargana@gmail.com +351 928154583

Lisbon

João Pargana

Profile

Both musician and engineer, João Pargana combines the passion and discipline of an instrumentalist in the art of full-stack development. With few years of experience, he managed to fully implement large scale projects from the architecture backbones to the UI/UX animations.

Employment History

Software Developer at Goodright GmbH, Hannover

01/2022

Working as a Full-Stack developer for the Startup Pflegewächter (Goodright GmbH) to provide free health care subsidies to elderly German citizens.

Automate the tasks of gathering, processing and generating juridical documents with a techstack consisting of ReactJS/Typescript and Kotlin/Java/Quarkus/MongoDB, deployed in AWS with Docker.

Software Consultant at Link Consulting, Lisbon

01/2021-01/2022

Worked as a Full-stack developer for two large clients in the automotive industry.

- Implementation of OCPI protocol in all versions for the PRIO electric mobility group. Used a microservice architecture written in nodejs/express/mongodb servers deployed in kubernetes, with Solace as a messaging API.
- Creation of a UI library in Vue/SASS for Salvador Caetano Group, to be used in their DigitalStore brand. The UI library is currently being used in the Hyundai and Carplus webapps.
- Development of Microservices written in Java/Quarkus/MySQL to integrate all different Salvador Caetano car brands with DigitalStore.

Freelancer Mobile Developer at Max-Planck-Institute for empirical Aesthetics, Frankfurt am Main

10/2020-10/2021

Developed a mobile app for Dra. Julia F. Christensen's research in the ArtLab, to measure and process heartbeats and extrapolate an artistic sensibility degree. The implementation consisted of:

- · Swift for WatchOS
- Android/Kotlin for Empatica

Links

impargana.github.io

Skills

Typescript

Java

React

Vue

Golang

Node.js CSS

MongoDB

Docker

Languages

Portuguese	Native speaker
English	Highly proficient
German	Highly proficient
Russian	Working knowledge
Spanish; Castilian	Working knowledge

Hobbies

Linguistics, Philosophy, Coffee Brewing, Surfing

- PWA in SvelteKit for BangleJS
- ECG Detection Algorithms Library in Java

Trainee at PhysikOnline, Frankfurt am Main

10/2018-10/2019

Develop and maintained multiple eLearning tools used by the physics faculty in Goethe university in Frankfurt am Main.

All projects were completed with an in-house library created from scratch and based on the following technologies:

- MeteorJS/NodeJS/MongoDB
- TypeScript/LitHTML/ReactJS

Education

Bachelor Computer Science, Johann Wolfgang Goethe Universität Frankfurt am Main, Frankfurt am Main

04/2018-09/2020

Piano Artistic Performance, Hochschule für Musik und Darstellende Kunst, Frankfurt am Main

10/2012-10/2017